VIET ANH TRAN

Auckland, New Zealand • +64221926415 • tranvietanh1996@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/viet-anh-tran-ba15a3a4/ vietanhtran1996.github.io/

Software Developer

Passionate software developer who is inspired by challenges and always strive to create the best craft. Experiences in working a wide range of projects from front end to back end and also always keen to explore the DevOps world. Apart from software development, I also enjoy travelling and playing sports such as football or swimming.

Education

2013 - 2017

Bachelor of Commerce - Major in Information Systems and Accounting The University of Auckland

Work experience

2018 - 2019

Associate Developer

MYOB

- Works in a cross functional team on a product called Practice Online a web application that is used by accountants
- Develops and supports a micro front-end solution and other SDK tools where other teams have autonomy to develop their own modules and plug them into our solution
- This solution consists of front-end using React and back-end using ExpressJs
- Creates and maintains CI/CD pipelines
- Sets up different infrastructure on AWS using Terraform/Cloudformation as Infrastructure as Code

2017 - 2018

Graduate Developer

MYOB.

- Joined MYOB Future Makers Academy
- Rotated between different teams and had a chance to work on a wide range of projects
- Learnt and applied development principles such as Four Rules of Simple Design, SOLID, and Test Driven Development
- Developed a HTTP Server which is able to respond to different HTTP requests as well as serving static contents
- Worked with a wide range of technology such as React, Angular, ExpressJs, .NET Core, Docker
- Supported internship programme by providing mentorship
- Co-hosted workshops at University
- Co-organised meet-ups and brown bags

2016 - 2017

IT Intern

MYOB

- Joined MYOB through Summer of Tech Programme
- Developed an internal web application with the goal to further enhance employee experience using ASP .NET Web Forms
- The objective of this project is to create an intuitive user interface and to automate tasks to improve efficiency of internal processes
- Other tools such as PowerShell and Jenkins were utilised to automation
- Perform requirements gathering from different stakeholders such as people from HR, IT, and Payroll

Skills

Development Principles Four Rules of Simple Design SOLID Test Driven Development Programming Languages, Frameworks and Tools Javascript React ExpressJs Webpack Jest Cypress • .NET Core • NUnit, XUnit Databases PostgreSQL, SQL Server, AWS Dynamo Infrastructure AWS • Cloudfront S3 • Lambda EC2 • ECS/ECR AppSync • Dynamo Alexa Others

Docker

CI/CD Tools with Buildkite and Jenkins

Infrastructure as Code with Cloudformation/Terraform

Feature switch with SplitIO

References

Available on request